[
    {
        "question": "He cwæþ to him ðu wast ðæt ic ðe <em>(lufian)</em> #### - He said to him 'you know that I love you'",
        "correctAnswer": "lufie",
        "explanation": "Here 'lufian' is in the first person singular form '<em>lufie</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Eala ðu scippend heofones and eorþan! Ðu ðe on ðam ecan setle <em>(ricsian)</em> ####! - Oh you the creator of heaven and earth! You who reigns on the eternal seat!",
        "correctAnswer": "ricsast",
        "explanation": "Here 'ricsian' is in the second person singular form '<em>ricsast</em>' because the subject is 'You",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "He <em>(gaderian)</em> #### sum gehwæde andgyt of ðære bec - He gathered some little information from the book",
        "correctAnswer": "gaderað|gaderaþ",
        "explanation": "Here 'gaderian' is in the third person singular form '<em>gaderað</em>' because the subject is 'He'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "He het ond we <em>(answarian)</em> #### - He calls and we answer",
        "correctAnswer": "landswariaþ;andswariað;",
        "explanation": "Here 'answarian' is in the first person plural form '<em>andswariað</em>' as the subject is 'We'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heofonas <em>(bodian)</em> #### oððe cýðaþ wuldor Godes - The heavens procalimed the glory of God",
        "correctAnswer": "bodiaþ|bodiað",
        "explanation": "Here 'bodian' is in the third person plural form '<em>bodiað</em>' as the subject is plural: 'the heavens'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie <em>(hatian)</em> #### hiera hieramonna unþeawas - They hate the vices of their subjects",
        "correctAnswer": "hatiaþ|hatiað",
        "explanation": "Here 'hatian' is in the first person singular past form '<em>hatiað</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic <em>(timbrian)</em> #### setl ðín - I built your seat",
        "correctAnswer": "timbrode ",
        "explanation": "Here 'timbrian' is in the first person singular past form '<em>timbrode</em>' because the subject is 'I",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He eallum mannum <em>(lufian)</em> #### - He loved all men",
        "correctAnswer": "lufode",
        "explanation": "Here 'lufian' is in the third person singular past form '<em>lufode</em>' because the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðes apostol Iacobus <em>(bodian)</em> #### on Iudéa lande - This apostle, Jacob, preached in the land of Judea",
        "correctAnswer": "bodode",
        "explanation": "Here 'bodian' is in the third person singular past form '<em>bodode</em>' because the subject is 'Jacob'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie <em>(timbrian)</em> #### langscipu mid æscum - They built the longships with ash trees",
        "correctAnswer": "timbredon",
        "explanation": "Here 'timbrian' is in the third person plural form '<em>timbredon</em>' because the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie <em>(feran)</em> #### to Rome - They went to Rome",
        "correctAnswer": "ferdon",
        "explanation": "Here 'feran' is in the third person plural past form '<em>ferdon</em>' because the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "&THORN;a <em>(sendan)</em> #### se cyning to &thorn;am flotan Leofsig ealdorman — Then the king sent Alderman Leofsig to the fleet",
        "correctAnswer": "sende",
        "explanation": "Here 'sendan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>sende</em>' because the subject is 'The King'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "sendest",
                "explanation": "Here 'sendan' should be the third person singular past form '<em>sende</em>' because the subject is 'The King'. While &thorn;a resembles the second person <em>'&thorn;u'</em>, it actually means 'then'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Wyrd oft <em>(nerian)</em> #### unfægne eorl &thorn;onne his ellen deah - Fate often saves a man not fated to die",
        "correctAnswer": "nereð|nereþ",
        "explanation": "Here 'nerian' is in the third person singular form '<em>nereð</em>' because the subject is 'Wyrd'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "nerieð|nerieþ",
                "explanation": "Remember, the third person singular form of 'nerian' is '<em>nereð</em>' because it drops its 'i' in some conjugations"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic <em>(hieran)</em> #### &thorn;u - I hear you",
        "correctAnswer": "hiere",
        "explanation": "Here 'hieran' is in the first person singular form '<em>hiere</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic <em>(l&aelig;dan)</em> #### &thorn;one micel here - I led the great army",
        "correctAnswer": "lædde",
        "explanation": "Here 'l&aelig;dan' is in the first person singular past form '<em>lædde</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "læde",
                "explanation": "Unlike 'sendan', Lædan does not drop double 'd's' because they are proceeded by a vowel. So, here 'l&aelig;dan' is in the first person singular past form '<em>lædde</em>' because the subject is 'I'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic <em>(l&aelig;ran)</em> #### leden and grecisc - I taught Latin and Greek",
        "correctAnswer": "lærde",
        "explanation": "Here 'l&aelig;ran' is in the first person singular past form '<em>lærde</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "lærede",
                "explanation": "While <em>l&aelig;ran</em> takes an 'e' in the present first person singular, here 'l&aelig;ran' is in the past tense first person singular form '<em>lædde</em>' because the subject is 'I'"
            }
        ]
    }
]
